<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Semelit's blog</title>
    <link>http://bashnesnos.github.io/blog/en/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://bashnesnos.github.io/blog/en/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Alexander Semelit's blog</description>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <pubDate>Сб, 29 мар 2014 02:25:31 +0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Сб, 29 мар 2014 02:25:31 +0400</lastBuildDate>

    <item>
      <title>Localizing your blog with JBake</title>
      <link>http://bashnesnos.github.io/blog/en/2014/jbake_locale.html</link>
      <pubDate>Чт, 27 мар 2014 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/en/2014/jbake_locale.html</guid>
      	<description>
	&lt;p&gt;(Please disregard dates in russian for now, blog is still in development mode)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s get it started.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was inspired by this post &lt;a href=&quot;http://melix.github.io/blog/2014/02/hosting-jbake-github.html&quot;&gt;about authoring a blog with JBake and jbake-gradle-plugin&lt;/a&gt;; so my first post would be on the same topic (my apologies for too many &apos;posts&apos; and &apos;blogs&apos; in one sentence). First of all because it has something to do with Gradle (which I love) and JBake (which is something to learn) in the second turn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My first time blog was generated, looked nice. What can one wish more? Well, I wish there was kind of a localization capability. It&apos;s not common at all, but when you want something and it is not there - you are not completely satisfied. So I decided to try and &lt;del&gt;break everything&lt;/del&gt;add such a capability.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The idea is: localized pages during the build are put to a separate folder. Since the pages are static it is the cheapest and straight-forward option. Switching between the localized/original is to be operated by URL manipulation in javascript. E.g. the following transformation will occur:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;src\jbake\content\blog\2014\jbake_locale.md -&amp;gt; \blog\2014\jbake_locale.html (original)
src\jbake\content\blog\2014\en_jbake_locale.md -&amp;gt; \en\blog\2014\jbake_locale.html (localized)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;I.e. to switch back to the original in the given example, we would to remove &lt;strong&gt;en\&lt;/strong&gt; from the URL. Which will happen if you click &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2014/jbake_locale.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By implementing that feature we are saving ourselves from copying and maintaining all the folder structure in our sources for all the kinds of locales. A nice and automatic tool will bake it for us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Convention is the following:&lt;br/&gt;* Localized post file name should differ from original only by &lt;em&gt;localeId_&lt;/em&gt; prefix (in my case &lt;strong&gt;en_&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;br/&gt;* Add the localized templates into jbake.properties&lt;br/&gt;* Localized template name should start from &lt;em&gt;localeId_&lt;/em&gt; (in my case &lt;strong&gt;en_&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;br/&gt;* Keep the &lt;em&gt;localeId_&lt;/em&gt; in mind when populating links and includes inside of the templates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will open you the secret: &lt;em&gt;localeId_&lt;/em&gt; is being derived from your template declarations in jbake.properties. If you have a template with name &lt;strong&gt;en_&lt;/strong&gt;post, &lt;strong&gt;en_&lt;/strong&gt; would become one of your &lt;em&gt;localeId_&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here is jbake.properties of my blog:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;site.host=http://localhost:8080
template.en_post.file=en_post.ftl
template.en_page.file=en_page.ftl
template.en_index.file=en_index.ftl
template.en_archive.file=en_archive.ftl
template.en_feed.file=en_feed.ftl
render.tags=false
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;The localized templates list is bigger though (en_menu, en_footer are not an outstanding document types, they are just being included by other localized templates):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;en_archive.ftl
en_feed.ftl
en_footer.ftl
en_header.ftl
en_index.ftl
en_menu.ftl
en_page.ftl
en_post.ftl
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the moment it works for Freemarker only, I would go on with others if my enhancement would be approved. And in that case it would be my first relatively significant contribution to the open-source!&lt;/p&gt;
	</description>
    </item>

  </channel> 
</rss>
